<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This is an automatically generated file. -->
<Chapter Label="Chapter_RSGraphs">
<Heading>RSGraphs</Heading>

<P/>
 An RSGraph is a graph <M>\Gamma = (V, A, o, r)</M> that consists of
 a vertex set <M>V</M>, an arc set <M>A</M>, a map <M>o : A \to V</M>
 which assigns each vertex to an <E>origin</E>, and a bijection 
 <M>r : A \to A</M> which assigns each arc to a <E>reverse</E> arc. 
 There is also a map <M>t := o \circ r</M> which assigns each
 arc to a <E>terminus</E> vertex. Note the RSGraphs are allowed 
 to contain loops and parallel arcs. 
<P/>
 We created the RSGraph object for this package due to our use of graphs 
 having a specialised definition. For example, every arc in an RSGraph
 must have a reverse arc associated with it while a <E>Digraph</E> from
 the <Package>Digraphs</Package> allows for arcs that do not have an
 associated reverse arc. Creating a new object category for RSGraphs
 allows for both better error checking when using RSGraphs and to avoid
 conflicting definitions, such as the definition of a cycle for a 
 Digraph and an RSGraph. We provide functionality to convert between an 
 RSGraph and a <E>Graph</E> from the <Package>GRAPE</Package> package or 
 a <E>Digraph</E> from the <Package>Digraphs</Package> package. 
<P/>
 The name "RSGraph" arises from Reid and Smith, the authors of the local
 action diagram paper. This name was chosen to avoid conflicting with the
 <Package>GRAPE</Package> package. 
<Section Label="Chapter_RSGraphs_Section_Creating_RSGraphs">
<Heading>Creating RSGraphs</Heading>

<P/>
<ManSection>
  <Filt Arg="graph" Type="Category" Name="IsRSGraph" Label="for IsObject"/>
 <Returns><K>true</K> if <A>graph</A> is of the category <C>IsRSGraph</C> and  false otherwise.
</Returns>
 <Description>
 Every RSGraph object belongs to the category <C>IsRSGraph</C>. Furthermore, 
 every RSGraph is an immutable attribute storing object. 
 </Description>
</ManSection>

</Section>

</Chapter>

