<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This is an automatically generated file. -->
<Chapter Label="Chapter_InputOutput_and_Visualisation">
<Heading>Input/Output and Visualisation</Heading>

<Section Label="Chapter_InputOutput_and_Visualisation_Section_Reading_and_Writing_Local_Action_Diagrams_To_Files">
<Heading>Reading and Writing Local Action Diagrams To Files</Heading>

<P/>
 Local action diagrams made in GAP can be written to a file. They can also be read from the file into GAP. The format of these files are as follows:
<P/>
<Example><![CDATA[
<Digraph String>
<Vertex Labels>
<Edge Labels>
<Edge Reversal Map>
<List of Other Attributes>
]]></Example>


<P/>
 Multiple local action diagrams can be stored in the same file.
<ManSection Label="Writing_Local_Action_Diagrams">
<Heading>Writing Local Action Diagrams</Heading>
  <Oper Arg="lad, filename[, directory]" Name="WriteLocalActionDiagram" Label="for IsLocalActionDiagram, IsString"/>
  <Oper Arg="lad_list, filename[, directory]" Name="WriteLocalActionDiagram" Label="for IsList, IsString"/>
 <Returns><K>true</K> if writing to the file was successful and <K>false</K> otherwise.
</Returns>
 <Description>
<P/>
 Writes the local action diagram <A>lad</A> or every local action diagram in the list <A>last_list</A> to the file <C><A>filename</A>.lad</C>. The list <A>lad_list</A> must be a dense list of local action diagrams. 
<P/>
 If the optional argument <A>directory</A> is specified then the file is written to that directory. Otherwise the file is written to the current directory of the GAP session --- i.e. <C>DirectoryCurrent()</C>. The argument <A>directory</A> can either be in the category <C>IsDirectory</C> or <C>IsString</C>.
<P/>
 If the file <C><A>filename</A>.lad</C> does not exist in the directory then it is create; otherwise the file is appended to. 
 </Description>
</ManSection>


<ManSection Label="Reading_Local_Action_Diagrams">
<Heading>Reading Local Action Diagrams</Heading>
  <Oper Arg="filename[, directory]" Name="ReadLocalActionDiagram" Label="for IsString"/>
 <Returns>A list of local action diagrams if reading the file was successful or raises an error and returns <K>fail</K> otherwise.
</Returns>
 <Description>
<P/>
 Reads the file <A>filename</A>. If the optional argument <A>directory</A> is specified then the file is read from that directory. Otherwise the file is read from the current directory of the GAP session --- i.e. <C>DirectoryCurrent()</C>. The argument <A>directory</A> can either be in the category <C>IsDirectory</C> or <C>IsString</C>.
<P/>
 It is expected that the file was written with the <C>WriteLocalActionDiagram</C> function. Some basic error checking of the file is implemented as it is read but this will not catch all errors in the file. 
 </Description>
</ManSection>


</Section>


<Section Label="Chapter_InputOutput_and_Visualisation_Section_Visualising_Local_Action_Diagrams_and_MDeltaM-trees">
<Heading>Visualising Local Action Diagrams and <M>\Delta</M>-trees.</Heading>

 Stuff goes here soon. 
</Section>


</Chapter>

